It seems the preparations
have been completed.
(大蛇丸)準備が できたようね…。
(カブト)はい 大蛇丸様。
Yes, Lord Orochimaru.
I will have a new body.
(大蛇丸)
私は 新しい体を手に入れる。
その後の世界に 必要なものもね。
As well as what is necessary
for my plans after that...
フフフ… 行きなさい カブト。
Go, Kabuto!
あなたの帰り
楽しみに待っているわ。
I will be looking forward
to your return.
(カブト)支度をするんだ 幽鬼丸
出かけるよ。
Get ready.
Yuukimaru, it's time to leave.
(幽鬼丸)ボクの帰る場所は
どこなのかな？
I wonder where I can go back to...
これから行く場所は
ボクの帰る場所になるのかな？
This place I'm going...
is it where I'm returning to?
大蛇丸様は キミの帰りを➡
Lord Orochimaru says
he is looking forward to your return.
楽しみに待っていると
言っていたよ。
(幽鬼丸)
ボクの帰る場所は わからない…。
Where should I go back to?
ボクの帰る場所は どこなのかなぁ？
Is this where I'm supposed
to return to?
キミは 大蛇丸様に
期待されている。
Lord Orochimaru has
high hopes for you.
期待には 応えなくてはね。
You must live up to them.
(紅蓮)フン… ほどよく減ったか。
They've dwindled to
a nice number.
ヘヘヘ…。
うわ!!
(紅蓮)殺し合いは 止めだ！
Enough killing.
アンタらは 今から
アタシの部下として 働いてもらう。
From now on,
you will be working for me!
フッ… 行くよ 野郎ども！
Huh... Let's go, guys!
(紅蓮)フフフ… アハハ!!
In order to carry out
Lord Orochimaru's plan,
《カブト : 大蛇丸様の計画遂行には➡
幽鬼丸の能力を
引き出す必要がある。
it is necessary to draw out
Yuukimaru's power...
紅蓮に引き渡す前に
成果を出しておかなければ…。
I must produce results with these tests
before handing him to Guren.
そのためには いかなる手段も…》
I'll use whatever measures
are necessary to do it...
You really can't tell until you try it.
(幽鬼丸)やってみないと
わからないよね。
Huh?
え？
(幽鬼丸)脚絆の結び目は➡
Can't tell where to tie my gaiters
unless I wrap it around several times...
何回か巻きつけてみないと
思ったところへは決まらない。
本当は 巻き始めで
決まっているはずなのに➡
You're supposed to be able
to tell when you put it on.
巻き終わらないと
わからないなんて…。
But you don't know until
you finish wrapping it around.
フッ… 行くよ。
Let's go.
(サスケ)そろそろか…。
It's almost time.
Orochimaru's Hideout Discovered
(自来也)お嬢さん。
いやぁ ここのダンゴは絶品だのう。
Young lady,
the dango here is truly wonderful!
美人が運んでくるんだ。
美味でないわけないよのう。
Of course, with a beautiful lady
like you serving it,
there is no way
it can't be delicious!
Oh dear, don't call me
beautiful like that.
もう いやだわ 美人だなんて。
The dango sure is good,
ダンゴもうまいが お嬢ちゃんも
きっと うまいんじゃろうな。
but I'll bet you're much tastier,
ain't that right?
(ナルト)はぁ～ やっと着いたぜ。
We're finally here!
Pervy Sage, let's start training!
エロ仙人 さっそく修業だってばよ。
(自来也)何を言っとる！
What're you saying?
First, we wash off the dirt
from our travels.
まずは 旅のアカを落とさんとな。
ええ!?
おぬしの腕を治すのも
修業よのう。
Healing your arm is also
part of training.
ここの温泉は 骨折によい。
それに➡
The hot spring here is
good for broken bones.
Besides...
温泉は楽しいぞ。 グフフ…。
Hot springs...are so much fun.
取材じゃ～ 取材じゃ～！
グヘヘヘ…。
It's research... Research!
…って 変わってねえな エロ仙人。
You haven't changed, Pervy Sage.
女湯 のぞき見して➡
Weren't you nearly killed
by Grandma Tsunade
綱手のバアちゃんに
殺されかけたんだろう。
for peeking into the women's bath?
No!
(自来也)ノ～！
The last time I came,
I'm sure it was a mixed bath.
前に来たときは
確かに混浴だったんじゃがのう。
おかしいのう…。
Funny...
Maybe they separated the bath
because of guys like you?
エロ仙人みたいのがいっから
こうなったんじゃないの？
はぁ？ まったくお前は➡
Huh? Just what have you
been learning from your teacher?
師匠から 何を学んどるんじゃい！
わしがなぜ こんな真似を
していると思っとる？
Why do you think I do these things?
'Cuz you're a pervert.
ドスケベだからだろう？
(自来也)ドアホが！
You idiot!
イチャイチャシリーズの取材とは 建前じゃ。
The research for
the Make-Out series is a cover.
本当は 警戒するおなごに
悟られないよう➡
This is actually Ninja training
to make oneself go unnoticed
by women who are on guard.
気配を消す 忍の修業なのじゃ。
Yeah yeah.
あ～あ はいはい…。
Ahem...anyway, being here
at these hot springs
オホンッ！ まあ 温泉に来たのも➡
is really to treat your broken bone.
お前の骨折を治しに来とるんだ。
湯に浸かるのも修業だと思え。
Think of soaking in the bath
as part of training.
Pervy Sage, hurry and train me...!
とっとと修業つけてくれってばよ。
Geez... You're such an annoying kid!
(自来也)
ああ もう！ グチグチとうるさいヤツめ。
ん？
Huh?
No need to worry about this now.
今さら こいつのことを
気にすることもなかろう。
I've trained so that instead of...
relying on Nine-Tail's power...
オレってば あいつの…➡
九尾の力に
頼らなくてもいいように➡
みんなを傷つける力じゃなくて➡
rather than use a power
that hurts everyone...
守る力を手に入れるために
修業をしてきた。
I've trained to attain
the power to protect,
だけど まだまだ 足りねえんだ。
but it's just not enough!
Pervy Sage, isn't there
a long-distance type Jutsu that I can learn?
オレにも覚えられる
遠距離タイプの術って➡
何かねえのかな？
フンッ！
一人前の忍のようなことを
言いおって…。
Talking as though
he's a full-fledged Ninja...
《キバ : 大蛇丸かぁ…》
Orochimaru, huh...
((赤丸 : ワンワン！
(左近)多連脚！
Multiple Legs Barrage!
(キバ)おわっ！
ワン！))
《キバ : オレは誓ったんだ。
I swore to myself that
I'd never let Akamaru
go through anything like that again.
赤丸に あんな思いを
二度とさせねえ ってな》
(赤丸)ワン！
Akamaru...
《赤丸…》
Kiba, what are you thinking?
(ヒナタ)キバ君 何考えてるの？
Well, I was just thinking about
our mission to rescue Sasuke.
いや…。 サスケの
奪還任務のときを思い出してな。
But this time...
今回のが
もし本当に 大蛇丸のアジトなら➡
if it's really gonna be at
Orochimaru's hideout,
また 前のときみてえのが
出てくるかもしれねえ。
maybe the same type of people
will appear...
What? Getting nervous?
(カカシ)なんだ？ おじ気づいたか？
Just the opposite, Kakashi Sensei!
逆だぜ カカシ先生！
In addition to Shikamaru, word has it that
even Naruto beat the Akatsuki.
シカマルはともかく あのナルトも
暁を倒したって話じゃねえか。
I've been training hard too.
アイツらにだって
負けねえってところ➡
I have to show the others
that I won't lose either!
見せてやんねえとな！
(赤丸)ワン！
Then I'll have to demonstrate
the results of my training too.
(シノ)ならば オレも修業の成果を
見せねばなるまい。
Huh?
あん？
なぜなら➡
That's because unlike you guys,
お前たちと違って
オレは 同期メンバーとの任務に➡
I've rarely been on missions consistently
with the same members.
ほとんど
参加したことがないからだ。
Are you still bitter
お前 まだ前の任務に
参加できなかったことを➡
because you couldn't be a part
of the last mission?
根に持ってんのか？
That plus the fact that Naruto didn't
even recognize his comrade's face.
それというのも➡
ナルトが仲間の顔すら
忘れてしまっていたからだ。
そりゃ ナルトじゃなくたって
わかんねえよ！
Of course, Naruto wouldn't
recognize you!
Your face is practically
covered in that get-up!
お前のそのかっこ
ほとんど顔 隠れてるじゃねえか。
That shouldn't matter...
among comrades.
そんなことはないはずだ！
仲間なら…。
C'mon, let's all do our best together.
もう！
みんなで一緒にがんばろうよ！
I won't lose either!
《私だって負けない！
I've done my best
so that Naruto will acknowledge me.
ナルト君に認めてもらえるように
がんばってきたんだから！》
Before I knew it,
《知らないうちに みんな
たくましくなってやがる。
they've all become
so strong and reliable.
ふっ！ アイツもか》
Even him.
Pervy Sage, do you think I've gotten
a bit stronger at least?
エロ仙人。 オレも ちっとは
強くなってきてんのかなぁ…。
なにを言っとる。
What are you saying?
You're the same novice
you were three years ago.
お前なんぞ
３年前のひよっこのままよ。
I see... I guess so...
そっか… だよな。
これじゃあな…。
((賢いってのが そういうことなら
オレは 一生 バカでいい！
If that's what being wise means,
then I don't care if I'm a fool
for the rest of my life.
Even without a teacher,
１人でも
もっと すげぇ術 編み出して➡
I'll create some awesome Jutsu
and rescue Sasuke, no matter what!
(サスケは 絶対 助ける！))
お前 ３年前と
気持は変わらぬのか？
Tell me...have your feelings changed
since three years ago?
I never take back my word.
That's my Ninja Way!
言ったことは曲げねえ！
それが オレの忍道だ！
Hmm, I guess so.
フンッ！ そうだったのう。
《自来也 : わしが友を思い
得たものは➡
I was concerned about my friend,
and what I gained from it was
a sense of helplessness and regret.
己の無力感と 後悔。
Yet Naruto has lived
わしの あきらめた思いを
ナルトは ３年間あきらめず➡
with the same regret for three years
without giving up
友を…。
on his friend...
He has never forgotten Sasuke
and has continued to train...
サスケのことを思い続けて
修業を続けてきた。
Earnest in his desire to bring
Sasuke back home to Hidden Leaf Village.
ただ ひたすら
木ノ葉に連れて帰ろうと。
Even if his own body is battered...
テメエの体をボロボロにしながら…》
フンッ！ バカはバカなりに
成長したと認めてやるわい！
The idiot has matured in his idiot way.
I'll acknowledge that.
ちょびっとだがな。
Just a little bit.
Really?
そっか？
でも アイツを連れ戻すには➡
But in order to bring him back,
I've gotta get much stronger.
もっともっと
強くなんねえとな。
フッ！
《コヤツなら…》
Maybe he can...
They say, "a place where
someone still thinks of you;
(自来也)
思っているヤツがいるところが➡
帰ってくる場所だって
いうからのう。
that's a place you can call home."
うん？
Yeah.
あぁ…。
This is...
(カカシ)これが
情報を寄こした暗部の…。
the Anbu Black Ops who
sent the message...
What is it? You sense something?
どうした？ 何か感じたのか!?
This is more than just a sense,
right, Akamaru?
感じるなんてもんじゃねえよな！
赤丸。
ワン！
The smell of death.
死臭だ！ この先に
かなりの数の死体があるぜ！
There're quite a few dead bodies
up ahead.
My nose is pretty sharp,
but...which way?
オレの鼻も
結構 効くつもりなんだけどね。
どっちだ？
こっちだ！
This way.
慎重にいくぞ。
Proceed with caution.
(カカシ)これは…！
This is...!
うああっ… 助けて…。
H-Help...
呪印だ！
A Curse Mark!
This guy has Orochimaru's Curse Mark!
(キバ)コイツ…
大蛇丸の呪印を受けたんだ。
《カカシ : ここが
大蛇丸のアジトであることは➡
Without a doubt,
this is Orochimaru's hideout.
まず間違いないだろう。 だが…
いったい何があったんだ…？》
However...
What happened here?!
(ヒナタ)消え入りそうなチャクラが…➡
Faint traces of Chakra!
One...two... There are so many!
１つ… ２つ… 大勢いるわ。
いくぜ カカシ先生！
Let's go, Kakashi Sensei!
We have no time to waste.
時をムダにすべきではない。
(カカシ)
トラップに警戒しろよ。 行くぞ！
Be wary of traps. Let's go.
ひどい…。
(キバ)何だ？ こりゃ…。
How terrible...
What is this?!
(シノ)状況から見て お互い
やり合ったようだな。
Looks like they fought each other.
仲間割れか？
A split in the ranks?
(カカシ)それは 連中から
聞いてみるとするか。
We'd better find out from them.
ワン！
どうした？ 赤丸。
What's the matter, Akamaru?!
しまった！
Dammit!
(カカシ)赤丸が脱出路を
見つけてくれなければ➡
We'd have been in big trouble if
Akamaru hadn't found
an escape route.
危なかった…。
(赤丸)ワン！
(キバ)ヘヘ よくやったぞ 赤丸。
Heh heh, Good boy, Akamaru!
だが ワナを張ってやがったとはな。
But to think they laid a trap.
(シノ)そうとは思えないな。
(キバ)うん？
I don't think so.
(キバ)オレたちの接近を 敵が
気づいていたとは考えられない。
I don't think the enemy
knew that we were close.
あのトラップは 情報を残さないよう
アジトそのものを消去するため…。
That trap was set to
destroy any evidence;
to destroy the hideout itself.
まだ生きている人もいたのに！
But there were survivors...!
ああ… ひどいやり方だ。
Yeah... what a cruel thing to do.
許せねえな 大蛇丸の野郎…。
I can't forgive him,
that Orochimaru!
ワン！
(紅蓮)グズグズしてんじゃないよ！
Quit wasting time!
(カカシ)大蛇丸のアジトを
突き止める という任務は➡
We've succeeded in our mission
to locate Orochimaru's hideout, but...
一応 達成できたんだが…。
(シノ)任務が達成できた
とはいえない。
We can't say we succeeded.
ほう？
Because we can't return
to the village
なぜなら 大蛇丸の情報なしには
里に戻るわけにはいかないからだ。
without any information
about Orochimaru.
(キバ)そのとおりだぜ カカシ先生！
He's right, Kakashi Sensei!
(ヒナタ)あの… 情報なら
まだ途切れていません。
Um... We can still gather information.
敵は 時限装置を仕掛けた…。
つまり ここから➡
The enemy set a time device here...
In other words, there are people
who left this site.
出て行った人たちがいる
ということです。
そういうことだな。
You're right. The enemy who
has information is still close by.
情報を持った敵は
まだ近くにいる。
なら 決まりだ。
ソイツらを追うぜ！
Then it's decided!
Let's pursue them.
索敵なら任せろ。
Leave the enemy search to me.
なぜなら オレの寄壊蟲の
得意とするところだからだ。
This is a specialty of
my Parasitic Insects.
んだと？ オレと
赤丸の鼻を忘れてもらっちゃ➡
Hey! Don't forget
my Akamaru's sharp nose!
困るぜ！
ワン！
わ… 私だって…。
E-Even I...!
オレたちは どこへ
向かっているんだろうな？
Where are we headed?
ケッ！ 大蛇丸のアジトだろうが。
Heh, isn't it Orochimaru's hideout?
お前 それが
どういう意味だか➡
Do you understand what
that means?
わかっているのか？
((大蛇丸 : フフフフフフ…。
やめろ… やめてくれ!!
S-Stop... Please stop!
(フフフフフフフ…))
アイツに 体 いじくられて
次も助かるって保証はねえ。
There's no guarantee
we're safe
if he messes around
with our bodies again.
確かに…。
That's for sure...
で… でも 大蛇丸 怖い…。
さ… 逆らえない…。
B-But I'm scared of Orochimaru...
I can't defy him...
Right now, it's only that woman.
今は あの女だけだ。
Y-You're right...
そうだぜ。 あの女１人
やっちまえば オレたちゃ自由よ。
If we kill that one woman,
we'll be free!
そうだ！
やっちまおうぜ！
Yeah!
Let's kill her!
(紅蓮)誰が休んでいいと言った。
Who said you can take a break?
オレだ！
I did!
ひぃ ふぅ みぃ…。
もうテメエには したがわねえぜ。
One, two, three...
We won't listen to you anymore.
テメエをぶっ殺して自由になる。
We'll kill you and go free!
It's decided!
オレたちゃ そう決めたのよ！
10… 11… 12… 16人てとこか。
Ten, eleven, twelve... sixteen of you.
びびったか？
フシシシッ… びびったか？
Are you scared...?!
Well, are you?
バーカ！
Fool.
これだけの人数相手に
勝てるつもりか？ 女！
You think you can beat
all of us here?! Woman!
…ったく 悲しいね。 相手の
力量を計れないってのはさ！
How pitiful! You're not able to
judge your opponent's strength!
晶遁 結晶五角牢。
Crystal Style!
Crystal Prison!
My insects have detected the enemy.
(シノ)蟲が敵を捉えた。
Geez, they couldn't even figure out
(リンジ)あ～あ 戦って勝てる
相手かどうかもわからねえとは➡
if they had a chance to
beat their opponent...
アイツら 体だけじゃねえ
頭もいかれてるぜ。
They're not only weak; they're stupid.
フフフッ… 自分は
賢いって言いたいのかい？
Are you trying to say you're smarter?
どうする？ ついてくるかい？
What will you do? Are you coming?
I-I...
(ゴズ)オ オレは…。
(リンジ)もちろん いきますぜ！
Of course! We're coming.
オレたちは逃げたんじゃない。
We didn't run away...
We just wanted to avoid a fight.
戦いを避けたかっただけでしてね。
《部下が１人もいないんじゃ
大蛇丸様に顔向けできないか…》
I can't face Lord Orochimaru
if I don't have any henchmen.
忠誠を誓いますぜ。
I pledge my loyalty.
いらないよ。 裏切れば死ぬだけさ。
No need to.
If you betray me, you'll just die.
(ヒナタ)翠晶に閉じ込める術？
A Jutsu that ensnares
the enemy in green crystal?
Earth Style?
(キバ)土遁か？
(ヒナタ)こんなの見たことないけど。
I've never seen anything
like it before...
(シノ)
寄壊蟲も同じ術にやられたようだ。
My parasitic insects have been
destroyed in the same way.
《まさか これは…》
This couldn't be...
Well now, shall we begin training?
(自来也)さて
修業を始めるとするかの！
Yeah! I'm ready!
オッス！ よろしくっす！
Maybe we'll do a simple Jutsu using
your Wind Chakra this time.
今回は
お主の風のチャクラを利用した➡
簡単な術を伝授しようかの。
A simple Jutsu?!
はっ 簡単な術？
うん。 お主 前回の修業の
旅でやったことを覚えておるか？
Do you remember the training
we did during our last journey?
I remember doing all kinds of things...
ん～ 何かいろんなこと
やったのは覚えてるけど…。
Remember,
you trained with the toad?
ほれ ガマと修業したろうが！
ああ！
うわっ！ どうも
ヤツだけは苦手だったってばよ。
Th-That's the one character
I couldn't handle.
You remember?
思い出したか？ あのときは
まだ早いと思ったが➡
I figured it was a bit
too early back then,
but you can do it now.
今ならやれるじゃろう。
ん？
ガマとのコラボ忍術じゃ。
It's a Collaboration Ninjutsu with a toad!
術と術とを組み合わせ➡
Combining two Jutsu to transform them
into one stronger Jutsu
より強力な術へと
変化させるのがコラボ忍術じゃ。
is known as a Collaboration Jutsu.
Hey, I know that!
あ～！ それ 知ってるってばよ！
暁のヤツを倒したとき
ヤマト隊長の水遁と➡
When we beat that Akatsuki fellow,
Captain Yamato combined
his Water Style with my Wind Style
オレの風遁を組み合わせて➡
to form the Hurricane Vortex Jutsu.
颶風水渦の術ってのを
やったんだ。
Good, that makes it easier.
(自来也)うむ。 なら 話が早い。
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せの術！
(ガマ力)あ～ら ジラちゃん おひさ！
ぎゃっ！
Oh Jira-chan...it's been so long.
ガマ力さん 遠いとこ すまんな。
Mr. Gamariki, sorry to make you
come so far.
(ガマ力)なによ 水くさい。
アタシと ジラちゃんの仲じゃない。
Oh, don't mention it.
You and I are old friends.
のわ～っ！
なんで!? なんで ガマ力さんが!?
Why...Why is Mr. Gamariki here...?!
Oh, Naruto. You're here too?
あら ナルトもいたの？ フン！
Unless the Ninja duo is completely
in sync,
術者の息が
ぴったり合ってなければ➡
a Combination Ninjutsu is impossible.
コラボ忍術はできん。
颶風水渦の術は➡
Yamato must have had perfect timing
with his Hurricane Vortex Jutsu.
ヤマトが
タイミングを合わせたんだろうのぉ。
それなら ムリムリ！
Oh, then it's useless.
Not him...there's no way
he can synchronize with me.
アイツが アタシに合わせるなんて
できるわけないわよ。
Shut up! Shut up!
If we can't, then it's your fault!
うっせ～！ うっせ～！
合わねえとしたら➡
ガマ力さんのせいだってばよ！
だいたい なんで オレが➡
Besides, why do I have to sync up
with Mr. Gamariki?!
ガマ力さんに
合わせなきゃならねえんだ！
お前の新術のためじゃろうが。
う…。
To perfect a new Jutsu, right?
From this moment on,
これより お主は
ガマ力さんと行動を共にし➡
you will train to synch your timing
with Mr. Gamariki's timing.
己がリズムと ガマ力さんのリズムが
ピターッと合うように修業するのだ。
Well, I guess if you insist,
Jiraiya, I have no choice...
ジラちゃんが言うなら
しかたないわね…。
B-But! Don't you think it'll be
an even greater Combination Ninjutsu
で… でもさ！ そんなら
エロ仙人と オレとで➡
コラボ忍術したほうが
すっげ～術になるんじゃね？
if you and I did it, Pervy Sage?
ガマならば 口寄せできるが➡
I can't be with you all the time.
But you can summon the toad.
わしは お前と
ずっと一緒というわけにはいかん。
う～ でも… え～とさ…
その術 ホントに つえ～の？
But, you know...
is this Jutsu really strong?
ふぅ… ガマ力さん。
Mr. Gamariki...
Watch carefully.
よく 見ておけ。
やさしくしてねん。
Be gentle, okay?
はっ！
Wow... I didn't know you were
so strong, Mr. Gamariki.
すっげぇ…。
ガマ力さんって
こんなに強かったのかよ!?
フフーン。
ガマ力さんの水鉄砲に➡
With perfect timing, my Chakra flowed
into Mr. Gamariki's Water Pistol.
タイミングよく
わしのチャクラを流し込んだんじゃ。
Your Wind Chakra will go well
with the Water.
お主の風属性のチャクラなら
水との相性もいい。
If you practice, you'll be able to perfect
an even stronger Jutsu.
習得すれば
より強力な術となろう。
より強力な…。
An even stronger Jutsu...
All right! I'll do it! Just bring it on!
よっしゃ！ やってやるぜ！
なんでもこいってんだ！
First comes special rhythm training.
(自来也)まずは リズム特訓じゃ。
リズム特訓？
S-Special rhythm training?
(ナルト/ガマ力)ワン ツー ワン ツー。
- One, two, one, two...
- One, two, one-!
(ナルト/ガマ力)ワン ツー ワン…！
Mr. Gamariki and I...
ガマ力さんとは…。
ナルトとは…。
Naruto and I...
- aren't compatible!
相性悪いってばよ！
相性悪いわよ！
Maybe it's not possible.
こりゃあ ムリかもしれんのぉ…。
You called?
呼んだか？
I thought I'd test you to see
the level of your power.
あなたの力…
どの程度まで きたのか➡
試しておこうと思ってね。
そういうことか。
I see...
フフ… 動じないのね。
You didn't even flinch.
You're very confident taking me
on like that.
私と やりあおうとは
たいした自信だこと。
I'm ready on my side.
こっちの準備はできている。
いつでも…。
Anytime...
"Loving smack," my butt!
I've had enough training
with Mr. Gamariki!
Come on! Combination with a toad
is the most important element
for the Collaboration Ninjutsu
using Wind Style and Water Style!
Even so. What can't be done,
ca